Diwali Puja. Los Angeles (USA), 9 November 2003
ديوالي بوجا.  لوس أنجلوس (الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية) ، 9 نوفمبر 2003
Today is the great day of Diwali.
اليوم هو يوم عظيم في ديوالي
That means today is the great day .....(?)
هذا يعني أن اليوم هو يوم عظيم..... (؟)
lights of your heart together
أنوار قلوبكم تتلاقى معا
to make a greater light
لتصبح نورا اعظما
for the world to move in a proper direction.
لكي يتقدم العالم في الاتجاه الصحيح.
It's a day of great joy, and those who join in this,
إنه يوم الفرح العظيم ، واللذين ينضمون إليه،
are spreading also great joy.
سينشرون أيضًا فرحًا عظيمًا.
But the problems are there, as they say,
لكن المشاكل موجودة ، كما يقولون،
but for us there is no problem because there is no darkness,
أما بالنسبة لنا فلا وجود للمشاكل لأنه لا وجود للظلمة (ام الجهل)،
we don't see any darkness anywhere,
لا نرى أي ظلمة في أي مكان،
we see lights, and lights, and lights.
نرى الأضواء والأضواء والأضواء.
Then what is the thing missing, missing is our sincerity.
ثم ما هو الشيء الناقص، الذي ينقص هو صدقنا.
We have to be very sincere with ourselves,
علينا أن نكون صادقين جدا مع أنفسنا،
because it is not just a borrowed love or a borrowed joy,
لأنه ليس مجرد محبة مزيفة أو فرحة مزيفة،
but it is from within the source,
لكنه ينبع من داخلنا،
it's flowing, flowing and flowing.
إنه يتدفق ويتدفق ويتدفق.
So that is to be awakened, and that love should flow,
اذا يجب ايقاظها، ويجب ان تتدفق هذه المحبة،
and our small petty things like jealousies
وأشياءنا التافهة الصغيرة مثل الغيرة
and competitions and all those things which spoil us
والمنافسة وجميع هذه الأشياء التي تفسدنا
must be washed away.
يجب ازالتها.
And it can be washed if your heart is full of love.
وبامكانكم التخلص منها إذا كان قلبكم مليئًا بالمحبة.
Today is a day of spreading love, light of love,
اليوم  هو يوم نشر االمحبة ونور المحبة
so that everybody feels enlightened and happy
حتى  يتنور الجميع  ويشعروا بالسعادة
and forgets these petty problems.
وليتناسوا هذه المشاكل الصغيرة والتافهة.
I am happy that you have been able to get some hall,
أنا سعيدة لأنكم تمكنتم من الحصول على تلك القاعة،
it's all luck that we got it,
انه كل الحظ انه حصلنا عليها،
people were so much worried about getting a hall.
كان الناس قلقين للغاية بشأن الحصول على قاعة.
But it has just happened,
لكنه حدث للتو بسهولة،
so you should know also that our destiny is all also
لذلك يجب أن نعلم أيضًا أن قدرنا هو الكل أيضًا
guided and looked after.
نرشد ويعتنى بنا.
You are already blessed people,
أنتم بالفعل ناس مباركين،
there is no doubt about it.
لا شك في ذلك.
And we should not worry about small things and small matters.
ولا يجب أن نقلق بشأن الأشياء الصغيرة والأمور التافهة.
It will all work out very well, you will see,
كل شيء سينجح بشكل جيد، سترون،
if you just leave it to your destiny, which is very high,
إذا تركتم الأمر لقدركم  الذي هو أمر راقي جدًا،
very great - in this your own destiny you will go very far.
عظيم جدا - في قدركم هذا سوف تصلون الى ابعاد جيدة جدا.
This is the promise of Diwali
هذا هو الوعد  في ديوالي
to you all, that you will reach highest
لكم جميعاً أنكم  سوف تصلون وتحققون الأعظم
and the noblest way of life.
وأنبل طريقة حياة.
Every word I say will be there
كل كلمة أقولها ستكون هنالك
to prove what I say is there.
لإثبات ان ما أقوله حقيقي فعلا.
Whatever petty problems you have,
مهما كانت مشاكلكم صغيرة ام تافهة،
they'll all be washed off.
سيتم ازالتها كلها.
All these are the messages from the Divine,
هذه جميعها مراسيل الهية،
you don't have to worry about petty things,
لا داعي للقلق بشأن الأشياء الصغيرة،
about money, about jobs, that's not your job.
عن المال والوظائف، هذا ليس عملكم.
Your destiny will work it out.
قدركم سوف يحلها.
You have a promise that you'll be looked after.
انه وعدا لكم انه سوف يعتنى بكم.
and are joyous in the highest way.
وستفرحون بأسمى الطرق.
I bless you all from my heart, all of you,
ابارككم جميعاً من كل قلبي، كلكم،
for a very happy and prosperous Diwali.
من أجل ديوالي سعيد جدا ومزدهر للغاية.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم.